Guide to the Delmer Daves Papers, 1930-1965
Department of Special Collections
- Folder D
  - IOC DFZ to DD re: answer to DD's reply to #11 above., 6/16/50; 2 pgs. (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - IOC DFZ to DD re: characterization of Beachcomber and motivations of other characters., 6/14/50 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - IOC DFZ to DD re: tests for witch doctor and suggestions for make-up., 6/10/50 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - IOC DFZ to DD re: Louis Jourdan's casting and suggestions for film appearance in costume., 6/10/50 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - IOC DFZ to DD re: possibility of Shushila Shkari as one of character roles. 8vo. with sketch on vso. of costume for film., 5/26/50 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - IOC-S Alfred Newmant to DFZ plus carbon copy re: progress report on music., 6/9/50; 2 pgs. (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - IOC DD to DFZ re: answer to DFZ criticisms #14 to #15., 6/12/50 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - IOC DFZ to DD re: importance of authenticity in songs and dances. C., 6/8/50 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - IOC DFZ to DD re: Ian Keith in Nightmare Alley., 6/13/50 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Incomplete draft, DD to DFZ. Ian Keith wrong for part. With 2 doodles., ND; 8vo front and vso. (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - IOC DFZ to RAK re: transporting cast and crew to Hawaii. C., 6/8/50; 8vo. (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - IOC DD to DFZ (returned with reply) re: using Walter Hampden as native., 6/12/50; 8vo. (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - IOC Alfred Newman to DFZ re: recommendation of Ken Darby (original in folder A, #18). C., 6/14/50 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - TLS Tad Nichols to DD re: footage of volcano eruption., 5/8/50; Size X. (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - TLC F. H Pough to William Foshag and Tad Nichols re: obtaining volcano footage., 5/4/50 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - TLX F. H. Pough to DD re: Volcano film stock., 5/8/50; 2 pgs. (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - TLC RAK to Tad Nichols re: price of leasing films of reuptions., 6/1/50 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - IOC DFZ to Billy Gordon re: Ian Keith for Beachcomber part. C., 6/8/50 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - IOC DFZ to DD re: selecting natives for extras., 6/8/50 (Box 29, Folder 16)
- Folder E
  - BW ph of sketches for scenes., ND; 2 copies, e pgs. each, 8" × 10" per page, 15 sketches per pg., 1 3/4" × 2 3/8" per sketch. (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Blueprint - exterior and interior of Laurence's hut, 6/24/50; 3' × 5' 3 3/8". (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Laurence and Kaluatest scene, 10 copies M and 1 copy C with SpNAD., ND; 3 pgs each. (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Test Scene for chief, ND; 2 copies. C 2 pgs. each. (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Test scene for Kahune, ND; 4 copies. C. 1 pg. each. (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - IOC RAK to William Eckhardt re: techniinformation (hotels, etc.) for production C., 6/6/50; 4 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - IOC Joe Cooke to RAK re: list of equipment left on Kauai for production. C., 6/2/50 (Folder 1)
  - Notes made by Ed Woehler, production manager, on production requirements. C., ND; 2 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Notes concerning technicalities of script shooting scenes., ND (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - TLS RAK to DD with OP corrections re: technicalities of shooting and editing and some personal news., 8/12/50; 4 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - TLS RAK to DD re: overspending on budget., 9/7/50 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - TLS RAK to DD re: reply to DD's letter concerning phoniness of real volcano shots, #8 above, with some personal news., 8/26/50; 2 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - TLS RAK to DD with OPN re: revising volcano shot scenes, and being behind schedule., 8/17/50; 2 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - TLS RAK to DD re: being behind schedule., 8/22/50; 2 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - TLS RAK to DD re: economizing shooting scenes by using less footage., 8/31/50; 2 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - TLS RAK to DD with FPN re: DFZ comments., 7/7/50; 2 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - TLS RAK to DD re: final tests for actors and notes on volcano film., 7/15/50; 2 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - IOC MM to RAK re: script change. D., 7/14/50; 8vo. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - TLS RAK to DD re: Jeff Chandler and his swelled head, etc., 7/17/50 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - IOC DD to RAK re: various eruption films available. C., 5/12/50; 3 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - IOC DD to Eckhardt, Blystone, RAK re: breakdown of scenes., ND; 10 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - IOC re: suggested lyrics. Original plus carbon., 6/13/50; 2 pgs each. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - List of Hawaiian musical selections., 6/13/50; 2 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - IOC to DD listing Hawaiian music of #20 used in Bird of Paradise., ND
  - Notes on culture and geography of Polynesia, ND; ca. 10 pgs.
  - IOC DD to Eckhardt, Blystone and RAK re: breakdown of sequences and locations. C., 6/6/50; 11 pgs.
  - Cast and crew list., ND; 3 pgs.
  - TLC W. G. Eckhardt to DD re: staff and cast list., 9/28/50; 3 pgs. T and 2 pgs. M.
  - Rev. movement list for Hawaiian locations. M., 7/13/50; 9 pgs.
  - IOC DD to Bill Gordon and Bill Mayberry re: possible suggestions for supporting roles., ND; 7 1/4" × 8 3/8". 2 pgs.
  - List of dandidates for supporting roles. C., 6/16/50; 2 pgs.
  - IOC DD to RAK re: leasing boat used in picture. C., 6/12/50; 2 copies, 1 pg each
  - Cablegram RAK to F. Herman re: asking for eruption film., 6/20/50; 8vo.
  - TLC DD to Sterling Hayden re: thanks for Gibbing book on Hawaii., 6/21/50
  - IOC DD to RAK re: itinerary conflicts., 6/21/50
  - IOC Irene Brooks to DD re: designing wig., 6/23/50; 8vo.
- Bird of Paradise Part II, 1950
  - TLS Miss Cecil Weston to DD re: complimenting on great success of Bird of Paradise and asking for job., 10/5/50; 8vo. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - 12 page synopsis of scenario for original play for Bird of Paradise, ND
  - Rev. Final SP by DD including p scene sketches, 7/14/50; (80 pgs, 12 per pg., 1 3/4" × 2 3/8") and FPpNAD. M. 130 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Final script, 6/19/50; 2 copies, 1 with PN. M. 132 pgs. each. (Box 30, Folder 5 and 6)
    5
  - 1st Draft Continuity. M., 6/1/50; 130 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - SP by DD. M., 4/21/50; 120 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Original SP by DD., ND; 77 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Original SP by DD-rewrite incorporating local customs., ND; 119 pgs. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Outline of Bird of Paradise by DD. C., 3/21/50; 38 pgs. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Original play by Richard Walton Tully., ND; 154 pgs. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Rev. final SP by DD. M., 7/14/50; 130 pgs. (Box 31, Folder 3)
- Daybreak in Bali, 1951; (20CF)
  - IOC DD to Casey Robinson re: notes on story and characterization, The Girl from Bali. With FpN., ND; 4 pgs. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - IOC DD to Casey Robinson re: same subject as above. C., 4/11/51; 5 pgs.
  - Characterization of story., ND; 4 pgs.
  - Notes on setting for movie - Bali Island on volcanic belt including 200 pages of research notes on weather and vegetation, native words and meanings and cultural background., ND (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Bibliography for Bali story. M., ND; 4 pgs. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - [UNK] of common proper and personal names, ND; 3 pgs.
  - p sketches of 2 women's heads by make-up man Dick Hamilton., ND
  - Suggested titles for film with pN, ND
  - Sequence outline for the Bali story, ND; 3 C copies, 9 pgs. each.
  - Cast names, ND; (2 copies, 1 C) OpN. 2 pgs.
  - 2nd continuity outline based on story exploration by Casey Robinson and DFZ., ND; 1 original PN with 3 C. 9 pgs. each. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper extracts, May-December, 1950-true story of a white girl raised by Moslems, then returned to rightful parents against her will., 12/29/50; 5 pgs. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - The Girl from Bali, a continuity outline. C., 4/9/51; 27 pgs.
  - Exploration of early Western version of Bali story by DD (white child adopted by Indians)., 4/9/51; Original and M copy, with N. 35 pgs. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Daybreak in Bali, writer's working script with sequence directions. M., 3/26/51; 99 pgs. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Working script, copy 2 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Research notes in large binder, including cast list, description of sequences, sequence locals and outlines., ND; ca. 200 pgs. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper clipping - breaking down race barriers: review of fim on Maori-European union., ND
- Folder B, Correspondence
  - IOC Carey Robinson to DFZ re: explanation of possible adaptation of truestory of #12 above, with OPN., 2/2/51; 17 pgs. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - IOC DFZ to Casey Robinson re: comments on #1 above., 2/8/51; 4 pgs
  - IOC-S RAK to DD re: flight schedule to Bali., 2/9/51
  - TLS Bill Gallagher to DD re: influential people who would assist in filming., 2/15/51
  - TLS I. B. Perkins, book importers and wholesalers, to Miss Richardson re: request for books on Bali with color prints and possible substitutes., 3/3/51
  - IOC-C DFZ to Casey Robinson re: impossibility of filming in Bali because of hostilities to foreigners., 4/2/51
  - IOC- DD to Dasey Robinson re: pointing out difficulties of plot outline., 4/11/51; 5 pgs.
  - Memo, Casey Robinson to DD re: DFZ comments. A., ND; 4 1/8" × 6 7/8".
- Return of the Texan, 1951; (20 CF)
  - Folder A, Correspondence
    - IOC DD to DFZ re: approach of script for Return of the Texan., 6/27/51; 8vo. C. (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - IOC DFZ to DD re: likes screen test for Dale Robortson and Walter Brennan., 7/3/51; 8vo. C.
    - IOC DFZ to DD re: casting Jean Peters instead of Anne Baxter in lead female role. C., 7/7/51
    - IOC DFZ to DD re: cutting budget for film to $850,000 top price. C., 7/13/51
    - IOC Confidential DFZ to DD re: characterizations of firl in film and actress possibilities. C., 7/17/51
    - IOC DFZ to DD re: must preview to see is film is too long. C., 10/10/51; 8vo.
    - Telegram Al Lichtman to DFZ re: criticism that film title may be misleading., 10/27/51
    - IOC DD to DFZ re: new title suggestions, 10/29/51; 2 copies, 1 C. 3 pgs each.
    - IOC [UNK] DFZ re: censoring required., 10/30/51
      -not
    - IOC Al Lichtman to DFZ re: not changing title unless all agree., 10/31/51
    - IOC DFZ to Al Lichtman re: using new title Home in Texas and explanation for choice., 10/31/51
    - IOC DFZ to DD re: title suggestion Home in Texas. C., 10/31/51
    - IOC Harry Brand to DFZ re: changing original title., 10/31/51
    - IOC DFZ to Al Lichtman and Charles Einfeld re: changing to Home in Texas and getting someone to write title song., 11/1/51
    - IOC DD to DFZ re: rejects DFZ title suggestion and comments on Guatemala location for next film., 11/8/51
    - IOC DFZ to DD re: using original title definitely., 11/9/51
    - IOC DD to DFZ re: 2 extremes of criticism and need to preview again. Original T and C copy., 1/11/51; 2 pgs.
    - TLS Dudley Nichols to DD with pN re: congratulations on movie and some philosophical comments about movie industry., 1/13/52; 2 pgs.
    - TLS Dudley Nichols to DD re: Signs of Spring for movie title and more on views of movie industry., 1/16/52
    - TLS Charles Einfeld to DFZ re: why good NY reviews but not doing well in box office. Also about ad campaign in West and South and Dale Robertson's promotional tour., 2/18/52; 5 pgs
    - DFZ to DD IOC re: 1 movie distributor's ideas as to why picture not doing well. C., 3/15/52; 2 pgs.
  - Folder B
    - Promotional material., ND; 11" × 14 3/4". 12 pgs. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Tulsa Tribune- 2 folio pgs., articles and pictures-promotional material., 1/15/52
    - Chickasha Daily Express- contains article on promotional tour of star, Dale Robertson., 1/13/52
    - Lawton Constitution- picture and article on promotional tour., 1/14/52; 4 pgs., folio.
    - Advertisement, printed., 1/10/52; 17" × 22". 2 pgs.
    - Cast and crew list with addresses and telephone numbers. M., 8/21/51; 5pgs. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Location crew list., 8/14/51
    - Movement list., 8/14/51
    - List of possible title for movie., ND; 4 pgs.
    - Pencil scrath notes., ND
    - List of Arizona locations with PN., ND
    - List of scenes to be discussed in conference, with doodles on sheet., ND; 2 pgs.
    - Sequence shotting schedule for Adrian Ranch. M and T with OpNAD., 9/4/51; 11 pgs. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Retakes and added schenes., 10/5/51; 3 copies, M. 5 pgs. each.
    - 3 BW prints of plow race on single photo paper strip., ND; Each 2 1/2" × 2 1/2".
    - Second Rev. Final script. M., 4/12/51; 133 pgs. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Shooting script with added cast, crew, locations and movement lists, p scene sketches, 8/14/51; (31 pgs, 12/pg., 1 3/4" × 2 3/8") and FPpNAD. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Blue print of the Adrian Ranch, 8/3/51; 3' × 5'. (Box 32, Folder 8)
- The Treasure of the Golden Condor, 1951-1952; (20CF)
  - The Guatemala Soory - writers' working script, SP by DD. MM, 6/8/51; 126 pgs. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - First Draft Constinuity- The Guatemala Story. M and C with OPAD. SP by DD., 6/19/51; 125 pgs. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - The Golden Serpent - Temporary SP by DD, 8/11/51; 134 pgs. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Rev. Temp. writers' working script - The Lair of the Condor, SP by DD. M., 10/26/51; 134 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Rev. Temp. - Condor's Nest, SP by DD. M., 11/8/51; 134 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - IOC MM to Script Dept. re: enclosing, 1/3/52; 5 revised pgs. of script, the latter in 1 original copy and 3 C, 5 pgs. each. C. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - p sketches (original and 2 photocopies) of Mayan codices., ND; 3 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Map of Guatemala filming site. p, ND; 3 7/8" × 6".
  - p list of sequence locations., ND; 3 7/8" × 6".
  - Drawing of a temple of palace (floor plan) with p doodles. p., ND
  - Sketches of Mayan figures. Blue print, with two notes on bits of paper as to production of codices., ND; 20 1/2" × 10".
  - List of Titles and French equivalents., ND
- The Treasure of the Golden Condor Pt. II, 1951-1952
  - Folder A: Correspondence
    - IOC DD to DFZ re: report #1 on Amazon story with comments about good movies. C., 4/26/51; 7 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - IOC DD to DFZ re: comments on Son of Fury and Sacred Jaguar with a comparison with Amazon Story., 4/30/51; 7 pgs.
    - Master breakdown of The Amazon., ND; 5 pgs.
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck re: comments on continuity draft of Son of Fury. C., 5/1/51
    - IOC- RAK to DD re: using existing stock for production., 5/15/51
    - IOC MM to DD re: notes on conference on 1st draft continuity with DFZ, DD and Jules Buck. M., 6/26/51; 10 pgs.
    - IOC DFZ to DD re: finishing draft of Golden Serpent., 6/26/51; 8vo.
    - IOC DD to DFZ re: making changes in script, as per #6 above. C., 6/27/51; 8vo.
    - IOC DD to Max Barsis re: approval of Franch sketches. C., 8/14/51
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck and DD re: comments on temp. script of 8/11/51. M., 9/13/51; 17 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - IOC confidential DFZ to Jules Buck and DD re: using Finlay Currie and Louis Jourdan. C., 9/26/51
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck and DD re: request for story and cast conference for Golden Serpent, 10/2/51
    - IOC MM to DD re: notes on temp. script conference, 8/11/51, with DFZ, with FpNAD. M., 10/8/51; 5 pgs.
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck and DD re: title change to Lair of the Condor. C., 10/9/51; 8vo.
    - IOC DFZ to DD re: question of authenticity of film footage of studio chateau., 10/17/51
    - IOC-S DD to DFZ re: derived historical atmosphere and comments on research done at Franch chateaux., 10/17/51; 2 pgs.
    - Same as #14b C., 10/17/51
    - IOC DD to DFZ re: Guatemala filming location and title for Return of the Texan. C., 11/8/51 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - IOC DFZ to RAK re; chateau footage and lighting in night shots., 11/14/51; 8vo.
    - IOC Jules Buch and DD to DFZ re: casting 2 lead parts and possibilities among actors. C., 11/15/51
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck re: contracting Cornell Wilde for the lead. C., 11/19/51
    - IOC Jules Buck to DFZ re: agree to Cornell Wilde. C., 11/20/51; 8vo.
    - IOC LS to Billy Gordon re: using Constance Smith. C., 11/29/51; 8vo.
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck and DD re: keeping honesty and reality in film. C., 11/30/51
    - IOC Jules Buck and DD to DFZ re: outline of wardrobe arrangements. C., 12/3/51; 2 pgs.
    - Same as #23. C., 12/3/51
    - TLC-S DD to Dean Acheson re: thanks for assistance given by U.S. Embassy in Guatemala., 12/3/51; 2 pgs.
    - TLC JIB to JSJ re: censoring script, FPN., 12/4/51; 2 pgs.
    - IOC-S Jules Buck to DFZ re: testing for Anne Bancroft, Fay Way and Konstantine Shay; problems with Bancroft's test., 12/17/51; 8vo.
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck re: compliments for first rushes/ C., 12/19/51; 8vo.
    - IOC DFZ to Jules buck and DD re: compliments on rushes, suggestions on Cornel Wilde's and Macready's acting. C., 12/22/51; 8vo.
    - TLC JIB to JSJ re: addition of line by censorship board., 1/16/52
    - IOC DD to Al Newman re: enclosing TLC of letter about music. C., 1/23/52
    - TL copy Ricardo Castillo to DD re: using some of his music in film., 1/14/52
    - IOC DD to DFZ re: editing of snake sequence. C., 1/24/52
    - IOC-S All Newman to DD re: investigating further the offer of 31b., 1/25/22
    - IOC DD to Al Newman re: Newman to negotiate with Castillo. C., 1/28/52; 8vo.
    - IOC DFZ to DD and Jules Buck re: comments on ending for scene. C., 1/29/52
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck and DD re: criticism of certain rushes. C., 2/5/52
    - IOC DD to DFZ re: comments on production. C., 2/12/52
    - IOC DFZ to DD re: night shots and fight scene-suggestions for changes., 2/12/52; 8vo.
    - IOC DFZ to RAK re: night shots and fight scene, and variety of accents. C., 2/12/52; 8vo.
    - IOC DD to DFZ re: accepting blame for hiring bad actor. C., 2/22/52
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck re: Jean Paul's scene with girl and grandfather. C., 3/21/52
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck re: suggesting a film based on Son of Fury., 12/4/50; 8vo.
    - IOC Jules Buck to DFZ re: agree on remake of Son of Fury. C., 2/5/50; 8vo.
    - IOC Jules Buck to DFZ re: suggestions for story plot of remake. C., 12/7/50; 3 pgs.
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck re: approval of ideas with go ahead sign., 12/8/50
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck and Jo Eisinger re: script writing outline., 1/19/51; 3 pgs.
    - IOC DFZ to Jules Buck re: too much material on script., 4/19/51
    - Additional scenes, inserts and narrations as per DFZ with FPN., ND (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Notice of title change to Golden Serpent., ND
  - Folder B
    - Staff list with telephone numbers. M., 1/9/52 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Guatemala location departure list. M, ND (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Wardrobe and hairdressers' plot for Constance Smith. M., ND; 2 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - List of line changes., ND (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Cast list with addresses and telephone numbers. M., 1/9/52; 2 2 pgs. each. 2 copies. (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Rev. staff list with telephone numbers. M., 1/12/52 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Directing instructions for interior jail scene and Marie and young nobleman scene., ND; 4 pg. (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Shooting schedule. M., 1/11/52; 13 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - List of child actors with descriptions in pen., ND (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Drawings of Mayan symbols with title possibilities. p., ND; 2 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - List of title change idea, with pN., ND (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - First chart, estimated footage per scene. M., 1/9/52; 19 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - List of interviews with DD with frequent, 10/25/[51]; P notes. C. (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Bit list for small parts. M., 1/9/52; 2 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - Interviews with French actors with pen notes., 10/23/51 (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - More interviews with with PN., 10/29/51 (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Notice of writing credit, signed by F. D. Laughton. C., ND (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Lines translations into English, Spanish and Quiché. M., ND; 3 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - Research questions for Guatemala Story. M., ND; 15 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - List of lines to be spoken in Quiché. C., ND (Box 33, Folder 28)
    - Key to symbols of codex., ND (Box 33, Folder 29)
    - Final script, Condors' Nest. M., 11/20/52; 125 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - Rev. Final Script-shooting script with Pp scene sketches, 11/30/51; 24 pgs., 12/pg., 1 3/4" × 2 3/8" each. 125 pgs. M. PpNAD. (Box 33, Folder 31)
- Never Set Me Go (MGM), 1952
  - Folder A: Business Notes and Correspondence
    - TLS Howard Dietz, Vice-President in charge of advertising and publicity, MOM to DorewSchary, advertising dept. re: liked script and enclosing memo., 4/8/52 (Box 33, Folder 32)
    - Memo, Howard Dietz to DD re: liked script but thought some scenes far-fetched., ND; 3" × 5".
    - IOC-S S. R. Monta to Clarence Brown with enclosed 8vo. memo to DD on same subject re: changing proper names in script., 4/17/52
    - TLS Felix Ferry to DD re: congratulations on assignment to picture with Clark Gable and information on contacting Paris representatives., 4/22/52; 7 3/8" × 10 3/8". 2 pgs.
    - TLS Felix Ferry to Vera Molnar Re: letter of introduction., 4/22/52; Size X.
    - TLC DD to Clarence Brown re: forwarding sketches., 5/15/52
    - TLC W. D. Kelly to Ben Goetz re: clearance of proper names to be used in script., 6/5/52
    - Cable Mannix to Ben Goetz, MGM England, re: addressing cables., 6/6/52
    - Cable: Ben Goetz to J. J. Cohn re: Trevor Howard for part of Denny., 6/9/52
    - Cable Ben Goetz to J. J. Cohn re: Trevor Howard refusal of Denny part and need for substitute fast., 6/9/52
    - Stanley Markham to Ben Goetz re: arrival preparations for Richard Hayden., 6/10/52
    - Cable BG to JJC re: requesting Hayden's measurements., 6/10/52
    - Cable JJC to BG re: using Russian Actors., 6/10/52
  - Cable JJC to BG re: Hayden's salary and measurements., 6/10/52; 8vo.
  - TLC G. R. Wolfe to Matthew Raymond re: proper names for yacht., 6/11/52
  - JJC to BG re: height and weight of Hayden., 6/11/52; 8vo.
  - JJC to BG re: amendment to #13 above., 6/11/52; 8vo.
  - TLS M. Raymond to DD re: shipment of 4 chairs., 6/12/52; 7 7/8" × 10".
  - IOC E. Hudson to M. Raymond re: shipment of chairs referred to in #17a. C., 6/10/52
  - Kelly to BG re: name changes., 6/16/52; 8vo.
  - TLS Irene Howard to DD re: Violetta Elvin cancellation and Theodore Bichel for Russian lieutenant part., 6/16/52; 7 2/8" × 10". 2 pgs.
  - TNS BG to DD re: enclosing #20b and #20c., 6/18/52
  - TLC George Balanchine to BG re: wants information on the use of dancers in film., 6/12/52
  - BG to Balanchine re: outline of ballet sequences needed., 6/18/52; 7 7/8" × 10". 2 pgs.
  - TLS Helen Gunnis (Christopher Mann Ltd.) to DD re: Phillip Reed looking for part., 6/18/52; 6" × 7 7/8".
  - ANS BG to DD re: congratulations on rushes., 6/18/52; 3" ×4".
  - Same as #22a.
  - TLC G. R. Webb to M. Raymond re: prohibited use of registered yacht names., 6/18/52
  - Cable BG to Kelly re: same topic as #23., 6/19/52
  - Telegram BG to DD re: compliments on night rushes., 6/19/52; 8vo.
  - Cable Kelly to BG re: use of Horizon for yacht name, 6/20/52
  - Telegram BG to DD re: investigating use of Sadler's Wells in movie., 6/20/52; 3 pgs. (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - TLC Dora Wright to BG re: lists different ballet companies and different schedules., 6/23/52
  - TLC G. R. Webb to M. Raymond re: thanking for bill of sale of yacht, Catherina., 6/24/52
  - TLC D. Wright to BG re: Festival Ballet only one available., 6/24/52
  - TLC Julian Braunsweg to D. Wright re: possibility of using them., 6/23/52
  - TLC Stephen Arlen to D. Wright re: inability to consider filming proposal., 6/23/52
  - TLS Dora Wright to DD re: sending hairdresser's and wardrobe stills., 6/25/52
  - TLC D. Wright to T. E. Bean re: thanks for allowing use of Royal Festival Hall., 6/25/52
  - TLC T. E. Bean to D. Wright re: granting permission to use hall., 6/17/52
  - D. Wright to BG re: why not use American Ballet company., 6/25/52
  - D. Wright to J. M. Dixey (Sound Music Bureau) TLC re: screen time for different ballets., 6/26/52